hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see oh it's raining it's meant to be
christmas as you can see i've got my new
skin on oh
we need to sleep
there we go thank goodness for that so
as i was saying i've got my christmas
skin on now i've used this christmas
skin for years
and it is
so cute now it's that they're mad at me
because i made it stop it was raining
it's meant to be christmas look look how
cute this is but unfortunately we're
only going
to be wearing this outfit for a tiny
tiny amount of time
because
today's the day we are going to be
judging
the they are really mad at me
i didn't mean to i just wanted to do my
intro
we are going to be doing the green head
finale so everyone the green headhunt is
officially over the results are in and
now it's time for me to go and judge
everybody's performance and their score
but i can't go wearing this i need to
put on something much more suitable so
and now i'm ready to judge
[Laughter]
i
look
fabulous
look at these little glasses no they're
not braces and no i'm not wearing look
it's difficult to work with my eyes okay
so i look the part i've got my little
notebook here my book and quill and this
is what i'm going to be taking notes on
now we're going to do a quick montage
because it did take a while to judge
everybody's entries into this
competition
and it was a lot of fun so
let's get started with
the convex guys
hmm
they've done something complicated that
i had no idea what they were doing
they've made like a conglomerate like a
lottery ticket buyers kind of thing
can you guys explain what you've done
i can't con can you from he just looks
at each other like i don't know
it's very confusing you see there's a
gentleman up there on the wall that's
the vex nose that's his glove of wonder
and mystery and cake and magic oh i
thought he was high-fiving me
oh no he's swatting bad people
are you okay well you know he decides
these things so what we did was we put a
dispenser down right and when you eat a
piece of cake it launches up and then
from that you got like 10 points 20
points 40 points 50 points or negative
points i may point out and for every one
of those we kind of divvied it up
between the commemorative peoples so you
have these beautiful hermits you had a
conglomerate of cub yourself
and who else was involved jevin
asuma yeah joe hills and tfc
all joints joined forces you had quite a
lot of people get involved here and then
you've divvied up
the green heads based on
a randomizer which is the giant high
five over there where are the green
heads are they in a vault somewhere they
are over here here
all perfectly organized i may point out
for easy counting all right
so are these accurate do i have to count
these myself that is that is indeed 70
heads although this one looks a bit
dusty i haven't been looking after them
hmm so gonna put
x down for 70 heads all right so we got
jevin with a hundred heads i understand
do you know one oh my god he's counting
again oh man there's just no trust here
there's zero trust okay yeah so that's
99 plus one all right okay so we put
jeven now for a hundred
now gevin gevin actually did have a nice
fault i will say he had a giant green
head volt oh that's interesting i'll
write that down
check
vault
okay all right
and
wait
this one is a bit of a tragedy what do
you eat
what do you mean wait what do you mean
joe hills has minus 40 green heads
yeah we had to burn 40 grand heads
on behalf of joe hills that's what
vexinos told us to do so we did it
yeah we don't make the rules why did you
why did you even put minus figures in it
it's just it's just how it turned out
man and joe hill's got all minus numbers
he got two two times consecutive like
you got minus 20. yeah
i will say joe does have a very nice
vault or he did have a very nice fault
until it was broken into by tango and
then
yeah ruined by gas there's a lot of fire
up there now it's pretty cool let's have
a look so joe
he isn't dead to you by the way yeah i
think i think i'm going to write his
in-depth
unbelievable i mean it's physically
impossible but he's managed to do it
when i did this competition i never
thought i'd actually
find someone that managed to lose 40.
unbelievable all right now we're going
to get this strapping chap over here
like in a british way
look at the hair look at the eyes oh man
do i get an extra point for saying it
britishly
um britishly it's not a word but okay
um all right so you got 70 heads oh my
gosh
it's really disrespectful really you
know why is he using why is he using the
to count stuff i need a piece of paper
to write down you could do the quick
match not even a real calculator all
right there's a 70 then
okay what kind of adjudicator would i be
uh if and not and i'm wearing glasses if
i didn't actually count them come along
all right okay
all right scar 70
plus
one for
british
[Music]
affiliation
you've already lost at the moment but
it's your it's your vault that we want
to see and we've got a couple more
people over here we got curb uh 90 90
heads okay okay man there's really a lot
of green heads just just in this one
place we have tfc with a hundred and no
oh
this is okay all right um don't take
points off for this i don't take points
i think tfc is going to lose some points
for this
110 heads now that is an impressive
amount of greenheads all right do you
guys want to take me to your to your
vaults because at the moment we've got
tfc
quite a long way in the lead by nine
heads
so your vault was here the whole time
scar
right in your base it was yes so grand
inquisitor follows in here
all right so you look around here and
you see this just beautiful secret
pirate cave but there's one thing amiss
and it's this block right here so if you
all stand on the elevator please stand
in here come on everybody get it in here
yeah everybody get it it's a little bit
cramped
okay
this is this is a professional elevator
here we go we all going down yeah is
this is this seriously
[Laughter]
this is my nether down here by the way
there is love in the walls so you hear
the lava
so you really feel like you're in this
is how i introduce and exited my thing
to make people think i was leaving the
nether
so in your video people genuinely
thought
it was here
brilliant i'm gonna yeah i like that i
like that a lot uh you won't know your
final score until i've adjudicated
everybody
but i i do like what i see here there's
no there's no
[Laughter]
thank you
oh
oh get me out of here
go back in
can you throw one
you're banished to the to the realm of
the nether
come in coming this way coming this way
so i had a riddle that people could try
and solve to steal steelheads
one of those is to put a smile on your
face which is what that skeleton is
doing right now
okay
so you walk through and then the one
part of the stash was back here all
right see okay
interesting so cub's to get some
points for being old school
okay so you've gone for
trickery which i like but you've put
absolutely no effort into keeping your
green heads looking um in a nice looking
place i mean they've got to look at
something nice so this was one of nine
one of nine by the way yeah i know it's
it's all it's all on it's all in the
book it's all in the book all right so
thanks guys uh this is gonna go
go down on the record uh you'll know
your final score i'll um i'll post it to
you or leave a sign or something uh best
of luck to you both
all right enjoy your accounting
so you have made your
vault out here in the end like quite a
significant way out in the end yeah yeah
yeah i mean we can't even reveal the
chords now it's you know we're out at
negative 2013 you know so yeah it's a
long way out
geez
okay so cuda i'm gonna hold on let me
get my book out let me
okay
tango
i like the notes all right
shall we plunge in here yeah
ah now
we both know what happened here right
yeah right at a green heads tango what's
yeah
is this where they were is this is this
the vault
uh it was somewhere around here until
tell us what happened go on i don't
watch it come on spit it out
wait some people already know let's
let's just yeah
let's inform the people that don't
very well then uh my heads were secure
out here so i thought
until cub fan and his con butts decided
that they needed to uh relieve me of my
skulls and normally i'd be fair game
because let's face it i'm i was i was a
thief myself that's how i got the
majority of my skulls but
it's more of the methods he used to
acquire my skulls that i i might have
some issues with
yeah so cub fan decided to use his
camera account which is in game mode
three meaning that they can fly through
blocks very quickly and look around the
server now kudos to cub for spending
hours
in each world that he must have looked
in the nether he must have looked in the
overworld and he must have looked in the
end as well unless he already knew
you're in the end he he knew they were
in the end because he watched my live
stream right so he put he did put some
clues together and i gotta give him
credit he was pretty smart but it's like
amazing yeah using the camera account is
a no-go zone for me that
i said like gentlemen's rules and that
is not gentlemen
my pinky is out and i i must say
this invigilator is not happy yes
so that's gonna go down on his record
i'm afraid
so yeah i did have i think like 300
skulls in here something like that
yeah now unfortunately because of the
way they've distributed all the green
heads i can't really reimburse you that
amount but i can take it into
consideration
very well very well
stealings did you do and who did you
steal from oh let's see i stole a ton
from joe and his little pac-man maze on
top of the nether i stole i had quite a
handful from false i stole quite a
handful from scar
and
uh a few more from cub just recently
over by jack sparrow in his little
parrot
so it was uh it was revenge that they
got on you yes and i saw the first two
riddles
and you and you solved the riddles
so basically in this competition it's
not just the amount of green heads that
you managed to find and keep safe but
also how you played the game and how you
hid them now i didn't tell anyone about
this because i wanted to see what they
would do naturally so i see people that
made a very fancy vault or have
significant protection they'll get extra
points i was gonna do that but i ran out
of time uh well you've at least you've
you've got points for the extra effort
in hiding it somewhere and you solved
some riddles so there's points gained
there so it might not all be lost yet
okay i will cross my fingers all right
thanks a lot then tango oh thank you
okay cleo you're up next
your vault isn't even a vault it's just
on your ship and
are you sure that you've found
green heads
i have found logistic green heads
legitimate
oh wait no no there's one
do you really is this a joke are you
taking the vic like
i found them that you found them they
don't even look like me
um
i beg to do that
and so does the fan base
hold on hold on
are you telling me
that you can't tell the difference
between that
and this
no i
did you put something on your head well
hold on i've got to take notes now i've
got to take notes for the competition
cleo
says i look like a wet fish
has one green head
meanie
[Laughter]
do i get bonus points for being mean no
oh
[Music]
okay all right falsey you are next on
the list
uh-huh
i've got a list here it's it's very
messy now after talking to everyone um
so i'm gonna say i'm looking at it yeah
i'm gonna i'm gonna count the heads that
you've got and then there's actually
extra points depending on what your
vault is like and how you played the
head game that's not gonna go very well
then right uh follow me
yep let's see where it is so so you were
quite risky and putting your vault very
close to home right you need to try and
see if you can spot it
look maybe to the left a little bit
okay so i clearly have to throw an ender
pearl in there's gonna be like a tiny
gap oh oh oh it's right here
there you go can i can't i just swim in
oh
oh wow this is
this is
creepy
it's a little bit creepy in here and it
gets super super dark
oh my goodness it keeps going down
yeah
it does so um good luck counting these
well how am i gonna count everyone else
was nice and like put a sign of how many
they've got water generally helps have
you have you done this before uh
uh good idea good idea there you go
we'll do this brilliant yeah so nobody
nobody found this no i don't think so
wow well that's that's a start because
everyone i've spoken to so far has had
their vaults raided at some point wow
okay
well i think that's all of them you're
in the lead already i can tell you that
rightly yeah okay you have
you have 100 200 250
272 green heads
that is
crazy 272
green heads uh-huh
and wait do i lose any points
well the ugly ball the vault wasn't
wasn't um broken into
you you had a a risky move which i i i
like that i like that
some people went and made vaults far
away that they'd never be found but you
actually gave people a fighting chance
but they didn't get it oh wait i need to
ask you a couple of questions actually
before i go did you steal anyone else's
did you manage to break in 20 volts
yes
yes i broke into cub fans okay and i
stole
like five of them
not all of them
no fight just five that's all i needed
and then i also broke into iskalls
and iskals how many did you steal from
iskall
five as well
okay and uh did you solve any of the
riddles
uh
yes two of them were already solved
right but i did get the one
in your tower which was the hardest one
so that we're going so
all right
oh yeah that will that will be it then
thank you very much i will uh let you
know in the post
where you've uh where you've come
okay thanks
cheers unfortunately iskal wasn't able
to make it here for the head hunt
counting but he told me how to get into
his vault and i can do it without him so
he told me to eat the chorus fruit right
that is so clever right there and then i
end up in his vault where there's
actually a bunch of green heads now
oh this girl you're here oh
hello green i'm here to show you my
vault
oh um that's very nice of you iskal
you're looking very
very slim today i thought you weren't
able to make it oh yeah i'm just here
sitting in here being swedish oh that's
that's cool scout thanks so um you wanna
show me what you got oh ya
so
this is how i get in with the chorus
fruit as you see and i am a really risky
person so i made a glass roof ah very
nice escala i'll put that on them put it
on your notes i'm really good today
i really hope that i win this
competition because i'm swedish and i
totally don't speak in this kind of
swedish accent all the time
well i can tell you this girl you're
gonna get some points here so i haven't
even counted your korean heads yet but
you've blinged out this vault it's so
cool it's loads of gold these guys are
sitting in style this is by far the best
looking vault that i've seen
oh yeah i put lots of effort into it and
money as you can see
oh yeah definitely so now i just got to
count them up
i wish i could help you but i don't have
any hands or feet at the moment so i
just going to stand here and watch you i
thought that's a that's okay iskall
that's fine i might have broken a few
things in the vault i don't mean to
steal anything
so iskali you only got 47
green heads
i'm afraid that's that's not many um i'm
gonna have to write that down on on your
list here
but don't worry because there are other
things that we can do
oh don't worry about that i'm just happy
that such a handsome man has come to see
my vault
oh well that that's that's nice of you
iskal
and uh did you do any robbing
no i didn't do any robbing but i did
protect my vault from a tango okay well
that that would go um defended vault
that will go in your your book
anyway i just wanted to say thank you
for making the green head hunt i had
lots of fun yeah
well that's uh that's it from me then uh
iskal uh thanks thanks very much and i
guess i get out the same way that i got
in do i stand in here oh yeah just eat
the fruit there i'll join you when i
grow some legs and arms
all right the buyer scout
ah now that's got to be the cleanest
entrance and exit that i've seen out of
all of the vaults i really like that i
really really like that so that's going
to get him a lot of extra points
well that's kind of everyone now so
time to go back to the base and decide
who the winner is
all right it's judgment time let's make
a little wall here and we're gonna do
some mathematics and hand out the extra
points that i mentioned
okay so it's pretty simple we've got all
of the contestants up the top here now
we're just gonna treat them all as
individuals for this we've got their
head count so joe hills had minus 40.
false had 272 and she is way in the lead
jevin had a hundred scar had 71 cubs 70
tfc 110 x had 70 tango had zero and
iskal had 47. so now we're gonna go on
to the bonuses and they're whatever i
decide
joe hills
so joe hills gets 40 pity points
for somehow breaking the laws of physics
and has a final score of zero false has
minus 40 for the cramped conditions in
her vault but plus 10 for the risky
placement
she also did a few riddles but
her audience did help her there so gonna
call that evens on that one
and she was actually a terrible criminal
as well as my notes say here ex poor
criminal extremely poor criminal she
could have taken more green heads but
she didn't i only only give points to
the best so that leaves her with a final
score of
192. now jeff doesn't get any bonuses
because i didn't get to see his fault so
he ends up with a final score of a solid
100 scar gets plus 54 good good trickery
he managed to make people think that he
was in the nether but loses 10 points
for damage on exit leaving him with a
final score of 111.
now cub
gets
minus
for
use of he gets minus 100 for use of a
cam account i don't like that one bit
but he's going to get plus 40
for multiple
volts
giving him a final score of 10 green
heads tfc i didn't see his fault he
decided to go conglomerate and
just make it easy so he gets -1 for that
phantom that we had so he gets a score
of a hundred and nine
and x i also didn't see his fault and he
did exactly the same thing so he ends up
with zero as well tango had his
very cleverly put vault
rated
so he's going to get plus 100
also pity points so
he was also very creative and he managed
to steal a bunch of people so i'm also
going to give him plus 50 points giving
him a grand total of 150.
and let me check my notes here i forgot
to add clio
clio had one green head
and she
called me a wet fish so she's going to
get minus 1 000 green heads leaving her
with a total of minus 999
and iscal
gets plus
120 points
for the best vault
in the game
plus
10 points for defense because he he
defended it with vigor
and plus 10 points for the compliments
that he play paid me he also had the
best entrance in the game
so i will provide him with 10 more
points now that leaves him with 197
green heads you might ask yourself why
would you bother even collecting green
heads in the first place
if you're just gonna make up the score
at the end well
shut up
it was a fun little game and i'm taking
these scores very seriously i wanted to
see how everyone would end up playing
the game i wanted to see if they would
care about their green votes how much
thieving they would do and how well that
they would protect everything
now
the there's a bit of a clash here so
we've got 192 points for false and 197
for iskall now iskall is up there
because he had by far the best vault out
of everyone's he actually put a lot of
effort into it he didn't exactly try to
hide it but he had a very clever
entrance there with the chorus fruit now
if i were him i would have hidden a bit
better but he also defended it he
actually killed tango on his stream
and he had a great swedish accent and
complimented me when i was doing my
accounting false on the other hand had a
lot of green heads and she figured out
one of the riddles but
the audience did help with riddles now
she actually
didn't steal as many as she could she
just took five and i guess that's that's
all well and good but she could have
stolen more so she got a lot of minus
points there for some poor decision
making during her time playing the green
head hunt not to mention her vault was
very well hidden and it was riskily
placed
but those green heads were suffering and
i just can't take that
so
i think what we should do here because
it's so close
i think we should split it i think we
should split it down the middle
and leave it up to iskall and false
to decide who gets what out of the box
so i'm calling it a tie between iskal
because he had the best vault and
decorated it the most and had the most
creative entrance
and false who did a lot of thieving used
the riddles and collected a lot of green
heads so because of those two very
different ways of playing they're both
going to win this round and
everyone else unfortunately has lost
especially joe hills and cleo who have
uh
very bad scores indeed thank you to
everyone for playing this game it was a
lot of fun
time to take this down now
so just because the points didn't match
up exactly
i'm calling it a tie for sure and
hopefully everyone will agree with me
if not
it's my game anyway
so i've been slowly hacking away at this
build
i kind of regret making this extra
circle because we're talking stacks and
stacks and stacks and stacks and stacks
you get the idea of concrete powder but
i'm making my way around ever so slowly
this is gonna make the base look much
better when it's complete it's just
about
tearing my hair out and actually getting
it done
you can see i've made very little
progress in the last few minutes you can
see just how long this takes so every
now and again i just log on when i'm not
recording and i slowly make my way
around and i'm gonna basically match
this to what i have there but i'm
definitely not going to make the
aquarium that said oh i need to breathe
also mumbo has introduced a
anti-shop whatever that is i think this
must be it because this looks new and i
don't recognize it
there's just a path here
what do i do ah instructions walk duke
round the course hit the button once
done have a nice day
okay oh do i really have to push him
do i really have to push him all the way
round because i can't actually walk him
and i don't have a lead
do i oh i don't really have to push him
do i i've oh no i've gotten him stuck
oh
why does everything i touch get ruined
i can't actually get him out of here
um
i've ruined it
yep got a diamond all right
thanks mambo that was a nice walk wasn't
it juke
oh dear
i also had an idea now somewhere in this
pile of mess
i have some gas tears
maybe i must have kept them
unbelievable i could have sworn i had
two gassed tears ah wait
there they are i found them now if i
understand minecraft well enough
no not like that i can make an eye of
ender and i can craft one of these
absolutely brilliant end crystal now
they're very expensive to make because
of what you need but i thought i could
make something really neat with it
maybe
i need to find a good place for it but i
want to make like a test tube where it's
sitting on top of an obsidian and
floating there
maybe up here where there's this giant
gap because this is where i hang out all
the time right so i want this to look
cool so this is the middle what i could
do
i can make it look like
there's obsidian coming from the bottom
and then it goes like that so it's like
it's floating in between the two i think
possibly more like that
and then we get rid of this down here
now hopefully this isn't a one block
center and it's two but
in theory if this is lit up properly i
really don't want to have to change that
because i
really should have checked before
placing that down because it's super
expensive to make
let's take a look
now i don't really like that now it has
to be placed on top of the obsidian i
kind of like it that it's floating but
it's kind of a drop in the ocean like
that
it does doesn't look right does it
doesn't look right at all
now can i harvest this back how do i how
do i do that
or is once i've placed it is that it
right let's just give it a go with the
old silk machine
oh
oh my goodness
oh no
oh what a tragedy are you it was are you
okay bud
just my pride hurt
i should have really known that that's
how that works what i didn't expect is
how much damage it does i was wearing
armor i think or maybe i wasn't you know
what i think we should scratch scrap
that idea completely
oh what a complete mess
that was absolutely spectacular oh my
goodness there's my elytra wow it really
went everywhere
all right let's fix this up
just a patch job will do for now
guys i i'm not gonna lie i think i'm
gonna scrap this idea altogether
something tells me that messing around
with this stuff
just isn't a good idea
[Music]
oh that was such a good take off
if only i could uh think like i fly now
what we're gonna do
is we're going to take this pickaxe
and we're gonna destroy this
and pretend that
absolutely nothing happened
okay so um nothing
to see here
oh my goodness
i cannot believe how stupid i am
sometimes
well anyway
i
i think that's it for today's episode
thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you enjoyed it and good
bye